嗨，妈妈
Hello, mummy.
怎么样，儿子？
How are you, son?
我很好
I am good.
学习进展如何？
How are studies going?
一切都很顺利
It's going well.
已经开始上课了
Classes have begun.
他的作息时间都乱套了
His routine will be disturbed.
让他睡觉吧
Let him sleep.
白天那么长时间你不打电话，非要等晚上才打
You let the day pass and then call specifically at night.
告诉我
Tell me.
你心情怎么样？
Are you in good spirit?
还挺好的
Yes, mummy.
翻来覆去问这个问题你不烦吗？
How do you manage to keep repeating the same question?
好吧
Okay.
那我就挂了
I'll hang up then.
好
Okay.
- 晚安-晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
你是在里面改坐标吗？
Are you revising 'coordinate' inside?
再给我点时间，兄弟
Just two more minutes, bro.
立不住吧？
Did it fall?
是不是立不住？
早就告诉过你们吧
Did I tell you or not?
杰图·拜亚和物理学永远不会错
Jeetu Bhaiya and Physics can never be wrong.
拜亚哥，再来一次
Bhaiya. Bhaiya. Once more.
你交了几次的钱？
How many times did you pay the fees?
我要是让你再交一次钱呢？
What if I say 'once more'?
看，他在课堂上犯困了
Look at that. He is feeling sleepy in class.
我有那么无聊吗？
Am I that boring?
我凌晨4:30偷了别人的车
I stole someone's wheel at 4:30 AM.
他随时都可能来找我
He may show up anytime.
然而这家伙居然困了
And this chap is all sleepy.
对不起，老师
Sorry, sir.
- 我整晚都睡不着，所以...-你刚才说什么? 再说一遍？
- I could not sleep all night, so.. - What did you just say? Come again?
- 我整晚都睡不着...-不是这句，再往前一句
- I could not sleep all night.. - No. No. Before that?
对不起，老师
Sorry, sir.
老师！
Sir!
大家都听到了吗？
Did everyone hear that?
他管我叫老师
Sir.
杰图·拜亚已经不是拜亚哥了
Jeetu Bhaiya is no longer a 'Bhaiya' (brother).
我现在是什么？
What am I now?
老师！
Sir!
不是只有巴特拉和饶才能叫老师
Batla sir and Rao sir aren't the only sirs.
现在我也能称什么……
Even Jeetu Bhaiya is now a..
老师！
Sir!
来，我应该给你点奖励
You surely deserve a prize.
- 过来-快去
- Come over. - Go. Go
- 来吧-干得漂亮
- Come. - Well done!
我的成功要归功于我母亲
The credit for my success goes to my mother Mrs.
苏米特拉
Sumitra..
快去! 去洗洗脸，快去！
Scoot! Go and wash your face. Go!
他想拿走我辛辛苦苦挣来的钱
He wants to take my hard earned money.
- 你翻脸太快了，拜亚哥 -有什么问题吗？
- You are so dramatic, Bhaiya. - Why shouldn't I be?
我这个哈拉格布尔戏剧协会的总管可不是白当的
I wasn't the Governor of Dramatics society IIT Kharagpur for nothing.
让我们继续
Let's resume.
-话说有一个漂亮小姐姐 -好的，老师
- A beautiful damsel. - Yes, sir.
一说到小姐姐你们就都精神了
Yes! Now you're all awake.. at the mention of 'damsel'.
- 馅饼新鲜吗?-当然
- Are the patties fresh, brother? - Certainly.
给我来一个
Give me one.
你怎么不吃饭，吃馅饼？
You are foregoing food for patties?
这哪是饭，这是垃圾！
It is not food. It is bullcrap!
离家才一个星期你就满嘴脏话了
Just a week away from home and you've turned foul-mouthed.
垃圾又不是脏话
Bullcrap is not a cuss word.
你就把这当作是身体的必需品
It's a body product.
肥料
Fertilizer.
阿加瓦尔先生曾经在课堂上也说这个词
Agarwal sir used to utter it even in classroom.
给我来点泡菜
Give me pickle.
你们继续
Carry on.
乌代，阿加瓦尔先生课上还说要刻苦学习、高度自律
Uday, rather than learning hard work, discipline..
你怎么就不学点好的
..and punctuality, you choose to learn cuss words from Agarwal sir.
还有你...都吃好几天馅饼了
And you... Munching patties all the time.
如果你再不好好吃饭，肯定会变得更虚弱
You'll grow weaker if you skip meals.
如果你变得虚弱，你就会生病
If you grow weak you fall ill.
第一周内生病的孩子
And the children who fall ill within the first week..
会被父母带回家
..are taken back home by their parents.
从此与印度理工无缘
And they never make it to IIT.
米娜，我就算吃了这些东西，我也会生病的
Meena, I will fall ill even if I eat this food.
这菜太油了
This is so oily.
-这是把卖油的打死了?-小声点
- Is oil free or what? - Speak softly.
如果被钱德鲁听到，我们晚餐就只能吃拌蔬菜了
If Chandru hears then we'll get mixed vegetables of all the gourds for dinner.
里面还有苦瓜
Including bitter gourd.
你还喝上酒了？
Still drinking Bisleri?
米娜，这是百岁山，不是牛栏山
Meena. Not Bisleri. Aquafina.
都差不多
It's all the Bisleri's are the same.
你为什么要浪费钱喝这么贵的水？
Why are you squandering money? Drink this.
水是无辜的
The mess does not make the water.
这的水都不解渴
My thirst doesn't get quenched by this water.
还有点咸
It is salty.
- 昌巴尔的水质... 很硬-很硬
- The Chambal water.. Is hard. - Is hard.
我知道
I know.
过去一周我都听到无数次了
I've been hearing this for the past week.
听着，如果你吃得不好，你就不能集中注意力
Look, if you don't eat well you won't be able to concentrate.
这样你就不能长时间学习了
Then you won't be able to study long.
你现在的问题已经够多了，为什么还要自找麻烦
As it is you are facing so many complexities why invite a new one.
听着，如果你一直喝这个，你就会浪费很多钱
Look, if you drink more of this you will spend more money..
如果水喝的少，你就会便秘
..if you drink less you will be constipated.
我已经便秘了
I already am.
你今天还是没拉出来吗？
You couldn't empty your bowels even today?
兄弟，我这吃饭呢，聊这个合适吗？
What kind of conversation is this for the dining table?
你刚才不是还说饭是身体的肥料
Wonderful! When you called this delicious food a body product..
你怎么不考虑合适不合适？
..was the conversation good then!?
还是拉不出来吗？
You couldn't empty your bowels?
你要帮他拉吗？
Are you going empty it for him?
乌代！
Uday!
我们去喝点茶吧
Let's go for some tea.
来吧，宝贝！
Come. Oh, Shivangi!
你咬得太狠了
You bite so hard.
你好骚啊
Raunchy!
米娜
Meena.
我们去喝杯茶吧
Let's go for a tea.
现在还不到5:30
It isn't 5:30 as yet.
你昨晚这套题了吗？
Have you finished the sheet?
是的，我做到第35题了
Yes, I've completed up to 35.
你完成了35个？
You completed 35?
你做得好快，我还在做第30题
You did it very fast. I am still on the 30th.
你怎么不一口气做完呢?五点半之前要做完
Why don't you complete it? It will be done by 5:30.
你们怎么能坐这么久？
How do you guys manage to sit for so long?
我坐一会就累了
I get tired in a little while.
别这么说
Don't say that.
昨天你作业都没做完
Even yesterday you didn't finish the homework.
如果你今天也不做完，那一定会越积越多
If you leave it today as well, it's bound to pile up.
我做不到
I am not up to it.
好好思考一下怎么合理利用时间
Then try to read the theory. Utilize your time.
我现在不想思考
I don't feel like it now.
这就是我一直想跟你说的
This is what I've been trying to explain to you for so long.
你知道吗
You know what.
读读《火烈鸟》
Read Flamingo for now.
这是一本轻松的读物，能让为你为考试做好准备
It's a light read and will prepare you for boards too.
拿着
Take it.
里面有很多故事
It contains stories.
一只猴子正在通过滑轮拉下一个物体
A monkey is pulling down an object through a pulley.
另一只猴子正在拉第一只猴子的尾巴
Another monkey is pulling the first monkey's tail.
因为它在拉它的尾巴，所以必然会产生紧张的气氛
Since it is pulling his tail it is bound to create tension.
瓦伊巴夫！
Vaibhav!
你的状态在我看来完全不对劲
Your symptoms do not appear right to me at all.
你需要一个聪明人的指导
You need the guidance of someone wise.
- 谁?-心理咨询师
- Who? - A counselor.
心理医生？
Psychiatrist?
咨询师? 见鬼去吧！
Counselor? Like hell!
我是精神病吗? 我抑郁吗？
Is this a mental problem? Am I depressed?
我有焦虑症吗? 我有自杀倾向吗？
Do I have anxiety? Am I suicidal?
我看起来像是个需要看心理医生的人吗？
Have I lost my mind that I need a counselor?
不管怎样，这里一多半的咨询师都是骗子
And anyways, half the counselors here are frauds.
我才不需要咨询师
I don't need anybody.
你需要阿普唑仑，能提升你的睡眠质量
You need Alprozolam, which is good for your sleep..
可以恢复你体内血清素和多巴胺的平衡
..and can restore the balance of serotonin and dopamine in your body.
乳果糖可以缓解你的便秘问题
And Lactulose for your constipation problems.
门口交费
Pay the fees outside.
你知道你不是医生吧？
You do know that you are not a Doctor, right?
就因为我穿的白衬衫而不是白大褂
Just because I wore a coat instead of an apron..
还有我的字写得不好，就能说明我不是医生吗？
..and my handwriting is not good, does it mean I am not a Doctor?
因为你没有执照
Because you don't have a license.
你为什么穿着这件实验服？
Why have you worn this lab coat?
穿什么
Don't dress for the job you have.
就是什么
Dress for the job you want.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
我知道你需要什么了
I know what you need.
克利须那神庙
Radha Krishna temple.
神会听到你的许愿
All your prayers are answered over here.
拿着这个
Take this.
用你最真诚的心写下你的愿望
Write it nicely with a clean heart.
从数学的角度来讲这是不可能的，米娜
It is mathematically impossible, Meena.
印度理工学院的座位远不如来这许愿的人多
There aren't as many seats in IIT as the number of prayers here.
搞毛线啊，米娜？
What is this, Meena?
你为什么要把我们带到这里来？
Why did you have to bring us here?
上帝保佑
Help me.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
这是很有必要的
It was needed.
来自一个所爱的人，而不是外人
But not from anybody. A loved one.
一个能够感同身受的人，一个亲身经历过这一切的人
Someone who would empathize. Someone who has faced this himself.
他跟我说起过你，所以我才带他来这儿
So, he told me about you. That's why I brought him here.
我来对地方了，不是吗？
Did the right thing, didn't I?
当然
Absolutely.
你确实很聪明
You certainly are wise.
当然了，他在马赫什瓦里教育
Ofcouse, he is in Maheshwari.
皮尤什
Piyush.
快告诉我你是怎么做到的，兄弟
You tell me how you managed, bro.
我现在吃不好，睡不好，还便秘
My food, drink, potty and sleep, everything is out of order.
你怎么知道我的地址的？
How did you get my address?
从你的父母那里
From your parents..
因为你不接我电话
..because you weren't answering my phone.
很聪明，对吧？
Smart, right?
这也是我的主意
Again, my idea.
非常好
Very nice.
我不会占用你太多时间
I won't take up much of your time.
我能理解马赫什瓦里亚历很大
I understand the pressure from Maheshwari.
跟我分享一下你的应对机制吧
Just share with me any coping mechanism.
我实在受不了了
I am not able to handle it.
患难见真情，对吧？
A friend in need is a friend indeed, right?
对吧，兄弟？
Isn't that right, brother?
你真是来对地方了
You did the right thing coming here?
难道不是吗？
Ain't that true?
谢谢你
Thank you.
太对了
You did the right thing..
因为我也受不了了
..because even I am unable to handle it.
看来皮尤什也便秘了
It seems even Piyush is constipated.
不是一回事，兄弟
This is something else, Meena.
怎么了，兄弟？
What's the matter, bro?
我不在马赫什瓦里
I am not in Maheshwari.
在过去的六个月里，我一直在上私教
I've been taking individual lessons for the past six months.
我的猜测是对的，米娜
My suspicion turned out right, Meena.
我跟你说过
Didn't I tell you,
为什么一个‘马赫什瓦里’的学生会住在塔万迪萨博，而不是维根纳加尔
what is a 'Maheshwari' boy doing in Talwandi instead of Vigyan Nagar.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
我爸是走后门才给我送进马赫什瓦里的
Dad got me admitted using influence..
但是第一次考试之后我就被排到后面的批次了
..but when the batch was shuffled after the first test..
最后一批
..I ended up in the last batch.
第二次考试我又是最后一批的倒数第一
The next time I was the last student in that batch as well.
然后我不得不退学，选择上私教
Then I had to leave Maheshwari and opt for individual coaching.
我明白了
I see.
这就是你不回我电话的原因，你这个无赖
That's why you wouldn't return my calls, you rascal.
- 对不起，兄弟 - 滚犊子
- So sorry, brother. - Get lost!
你要我怎么开口？
How could I tell you?
爸爸在老家到处吹嘘
Dad has bragged all over Itarsi..
我在马赫什瓦里教育
..that I am in Maheshwari.
是啊
Ya.
他确实爱吹牛
He does brag alot.
他在老家跟所有人说我没被马赫什瓦里录取
He told all of Itarsi that I didn't get admitted to Maheshwari.
老家亲戚朋友都认为我一定能考上印度理工
All of Itarsi feels I will surely get admitted to IIT.
是的，我们都有这种感觉
Yes. All of us feel that way.
是的
Yes.
我还很纳闷他的成绩是怎么突然飙上来的
I was baffled as to how he soared so suddenly.
我希望你的家人知道
I hope your family knows.
- 不行，兄弟 - 不行？
- No, buddy. - No?
上次我回家的时候
Last time when I went home for Diwali..
我本来打算把一切都说出来，结束这件事，但是……
..I had planned on disclosing everything and end the matter but..
但是？
But?
这是我有生以来第一次接到尼哈打来的电话
For the first time in my life Neha called.
尼哈 · 普罗希特？
Neha Purohit?
是的，你认识她的妹妹
Yes. You know her younger sister.
- 希尔帕?-是的
- Shilpa? - Yes.
她也想考印度理工学院，需要我的建议
She was thinking of IIT herself and needed tips from me.
所以他们两个都来了我家
So both of them came to my place.
尼哈和希尔帕？
Both Neha and Shilpa?
- 是的-还有他们的妈妈也来了
- Yes. - Their mom came too.
- 迪莎阿姨?-是的
- Aunt Disha? - Yes.
这是我有生以来第一次得到如此多的认可
For the first time in my life I got so much recognition..
我怎么能就这么算了呢？
..how could I have let it go?
还有，你知道吗，在谈话中
Also, do you know, during the conversation..
阿姨还跟我确认了我的出生日期和时间
..aunt confirmed my time and date of birth.
我也在为印度理工学院做准备啊
Even I am preparing for IIT.
我在学校成绩还比你好
I was a better student than you in school.
她怎么不来找我要建议
She never asked me for tips.
因为你在神童教育
You are studying in Prodigy.
先不说那些了，快帮我想想办法
Never mind all of that. Tell me what I should do.
你啊
You..
最好去看看心理医生
..better see a counselor.
喂，妈妈
Yes, mummy.
你在干什么？
What were you doing?
没什么，我在学习
Nothing. Was studying when..
然后一位无所事事的女士打扰了我
..an idle lady disturbed me.
她怎么能这么做？
How could she do that?
在你学习的时候你要跟你房东说清楚，不要来打扰……
Make it clear to your landlady when you are studying she..
我知道了
I got it.
我挂了，你继续学习吧
I'll hang up. You continue studying.
你心情怎么样？
Are you in a good spirit?
可好了，放心吧
Yes, mummy. I am.
除非我明确告诉你，否则就不要妄下结论
Until I categorically tell you never assume otherwise.
好吧，晚安
Well, goodnight.
晚安
Goodnight.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
“我没做这道题，因为我看不懂”
"I didn't attempt the problem as I didn't understand it."
一定要寻找线索，题干里面给出了很多线索
Always look for hints, so many are there.
在哪呢？
Where?
第一个提示就是这道题是人出的
The first hint is that the problem is given.
当出题者向我们提出问题时
When the maker has posed the problem to us..
这就意味着利用我们现有的知识是可以解决的
..that means it's solvable with our knowledge.
另外速度也给了
Secondly the velocity is given.
看到了吧，是不是？
See. Is it or isn't it?
那么速度只有在两种情况下会用到
So, it will be used in either of the two things.
能量或动量
Energy or momentum.
现在你要决定赌一把
Now you have to decide which gamble to take.
如果你还是没看懂，那么继续寻找线索
If it still doesn't make sense then keep looking for hints.
“摩擦”这个词看到了吗？
Is the word 'friction' visible?
是的
Yes.
这意味着不是能量
It means energy cannot be used.
那还剩什么了? 动量守恒
What does that leave? Conservation of momentum.
初始值等于最终值
Initial equal to final.
回答是或不是
Say yes or no.
是的
Yes, sir.
只需要把初始值和最终值等同起来
Just equate initial to final.
打勾然后看下一题
Tick it and move on.
在未来的某个时刻，可能在你开心的唱歌时
At some point in the future whilst laughing, singing..
. . 或者在上厕所时，你就会意识到
..or in toilet you will realize..
为什么动量是守恒的
..why was the momentum conserved.
好吗？
Okay?
即使你不理解这个问题，你也要解题
Even if you don't understand the question jostle with it.
你是做什么的？
What do you do?
解题的
Jostle with it.
是的
Yes.
一旦你学会了解题喝转笔
Once you have learned to jostle with questions and twirl the pen...
你就已经是半个理工学院人了
..you are already half an IITian.
来吧下一题
Come on. Next.
你要去哪，剩下的题你不做了吗？
Hello, bro. Didn't you do the rest?
老师，我只做到了52题
Sir, I only did up to number 52.
我明白了，你做了52道题，非常棒！
I see. You completed 52. Very good!
我这人就是不爱护环境
It's me who hates the environment.
我印150道题就是为了浪费纸，对吧？
I made a 150 page long sheet just to waste paper, right?
不是我不能解题
Sir, Not that I can't crack problems..
而是我坐不住板凳
..but I am unable to sit for long.
我心情不好
I'm not in the right spirit.
这是真的吗，还是另有隐情？
Is this the problem or there's more to it?
拜亚哥，他来了之后吃不好
Bhaiya, he doesn't even eat well.
他靠吃馅饼生存
He survives on Maggi and patties.
他每天喝矿泉水，甚至都不怎么睡觉
He still drinks Bisleri water and doesn't even sleep.
真的吗？
Why, brother?
是的，拜亚哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
你来的比别人晚
You came late.
所以错过了迎新会
So he missed the orientation.
他不知道在科塔生活的两个重要概念
He does not know the two important concepts of living in Kota.
告诉他，米纳尔
Tell him, Meenal.
两个什么概念？
What are they?
首先，杰图·拜亚不是我们的物理教员
Firstly, Jeetu Bhaiya is not our physics faculty.
他是我们的知心姐姐
He is our agony aunt.
能解决各种各样的问题
He solves all kinds of problems.
学术问题，非学术问题，个人问题，经济问题或者感情问题
Academic, non-academic, personal, financial or romantic.
即使你半夜喝多了
Even if your landlord has kicked you out of the house..
被房东赶出来
..in the middle of the night or if you've argued with the mess people..
或者是被警察抓到你看黄色杂志
..or if a Policeman has caught you reading obscene literature.
杰图·拜亚都能解决
Jeetu Bhaiya solves everything.
只要给他打电话，杰图·拜亚就能帮助你
Just call him immediately and Jeetu Bhaiya solves all the problems.
还有
And..
第二个？
..the second?
你忘了第二个？
You forgot the second?
是的
Yes.
每个孩子都是特别的
Every child is special.
这完全是胡说八道
That is utter nonsense.
你不是什么独一无二的人
You are not some unique personality.
你遇到的问题每年都会发生在成千上万的学生身上
These problems occur to thousands of students each year.
在准备去理工学院生活之前，你必须学会在科塔生存
Before preparing for IIT at Kota one must prepare themselves to live in Kota.
有很多简单的方法可以做到
And there are simple ways to do it.
如果你遇到问题
If you encounter problems..
解决问题
Jostle with them.
即使你不喜欢这里的水，也要喝
Even if you don't like the water, Just drink it.
即使你不喜欢这些乱七八糟的食物，也要吃
Even if you don't like the mess food, Just eat it.
即使你不能长时间地坐着，也要一直坐着
Even if you are unable to sit for long Just sit for long.
挑战你自己，我会坐很久
Challenge yourself. I will sit for long.
我根本起不来
I won't get up at all.
我要解题，我要读书
I will solve problems. I will read theories.
我要看讲座
I will watch Unacademy's lessons.
我要复习以前的错题
I will go through old papers.
我会睡觉，我会死，但我就是不会站起来
I will sleep, I will die but I won't get up.
这样的话，你做到了什么？
So, what have you done?
你已经把你遇到的问题转化为勇气
You have turned your problems to dare.
而勇气则与自我直接相关
And dare is directly connected to ego.
自我有许多缺点，但它也有优点
Ego has many disadvantages but it has one advantage too.
事情似乎是可行的
Things seem to be doable.
你不必长时间强迫自己去做这些事情
And you don't have to do this drama for long.
多少天？
How many days?
21天
21 days.
你可以在21天内养成或放弃任何习惯
You can form any or give up any habit in 21 days.
我以前抽烟很凶
I had a smoking problem.
一天两包
2 packs a day.
我戒掉了
I lost it.
戒烟之后我就在家里炫耀
I left it one day and after that I bragged about it at home..
给我的女朋友，同事，司机和司机的妻子炫耀
..to my girlfriend, faculty, driver and the driver's wife.
因此，我给了那个小贩2000卢比
So much so, I gave 2000 rupees to the vendor..
不要把烟卖给我
..not to give me cigarettes to smoke.
如果你向全世界吹嘘，那么世界就不会让你吸烟
If you brag about it to the world then the world won't let you smoke.
刚开始戒烟的时候我很难受，很想抽烟
I felt a little urge in the beginning and then some more.
但是过了21天，这种欲望变成了零
By the time 21 days had passed the urge was zero.
这就是你必须做的
That's what you have to do.
说点什么，是或不是
Say something. Yes or no.
是的，拜亚哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
乌代是个讨厌的家伙
Uday is a nasty fella..
但是米娜，你明知道你的朋友会这样
..but Meena, you knew this was happening with your friend..
但你还是没告诉他？
..and still didn't tell him?
拜亚哥，我..
Bhaiya, I..
你也一样，布鲁图斯
You too, Brutus.
你也一样
You too.
你注意到了吗？
Did you notice?
拜亚哥叫我布鲁图斯，‘布鲁图斯·米娜’
Bhaiya called me Brutus. 'Brutus Meena'
干嘛? 你没有一点幽默感吗？
What? Don't you have any sense of humour?
我很丑，但是我很温柔
I might look nasty but not from the heart.
当然，我是比哈尔猛虎的成员
Sure, I'm a member of the Bihar Tigers.
我肩负着整个城市和平
I have the responsibility of the entire city on these shoulders.
但是乌代 · 古普塔绝不会忽视他的朋友
But Uday Gupta never ignores his sidekicks.
因为你哥我是街头之王
..because your brother is the king of the streets.
我已经开启了'非学术'的年度订阅
I have taken the annual subscription for Unacademy plus.
给你开的
For you.
去吧，想听多少讲座就听多少
Go. Attend as many live lectures as you wish.
永远记住，你的兄弟是我，不是布鲁图斯
And always remember. Your brother is Caesar, not Brutus.
他下午三点才起床
This man rises up at 3 pm.
但是你不要起来，去学习
But don't you rise. Go study.
你在看什么? 快去学习
What are you looking at? Go study.
人不会讨厌他看不见的东西
One cannot hate what one does not see.
完全不要看那些乱七八糟的食物
Don't look at the mess food at all.
不慌不忙地撕一块面包
Pick up bread without a fuss.
随便蘸点什么，嚼嚼就行了
Dip it in whatever and just chew.
有时你可能会忍不住下看
Sometimes you may be tempted to look down..
但这就是你的失败之处
..but therein lies your defeat.
今天味道好多了
Tastes even better today.
不要喝常温的水
Don't drink water at room temperature.
喝冰箱里的冷水
Drink chilled water of the fridge.
人们甚至觉得冰镇啤酒都好喝
People even savour beer if chilled.
盐水算不了什么
Salt water is nothing.
干杯
Bottoms up.
这里的 x 表示块的距离
Here x is given as the distance of the block..
我们必须找到速度作为 x 的函数
..and we have to find the velocity as a function of x.
只要选择正确的选项
Just choose the correct option.
C.
你什么时候来的？
When did you come?
我来看看你
I came to check on you.
很好! 很好！
Good! Good!
如果你选择了 c 选项，那么你的答案是正确的
If you have chosen C option then your answer is correct.
现在我来告诉你这个问题的解决办法
Now I shall tell you the solution of this question.
是的，我吃过了
Yes, I have eaten.
我很好，精神也很好
I am all well and am in good spirits.
妈妈，你怎么能每天都问我同样的问题呢？
Mummy, how do you manage to keep repeating the same question everyday?
好吧
Okay.
再用点力，兄弟
Apply more pressure, bro.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
有用吗？
Is it working?
扁豆汤，蔬菜和面包都准备好
Lentil soup, veggies and breads have to be prepared..
所以总会有一个错误范围
..so there is always a scope of mistake.
在这样的范围内，厨师们肯定会犯错误
Given the scope, the cooks in the mess ensure mistakes.
这就是为什么一个人应该更喜欢吃自己不做的东西
That's why one should prefer eating what they don't make..
例如沙拉，泡菜，薄饼，酸奶和糖
..such as salad, pickle, papad, yogurt and sugar.
这样你的套餐就做好了
And there is your three course meal.
我治好了很多人的便秘
I have helped many people crap.
你的也一样
Yours is no different.
两口
Two puffs.
只要两口
Only two puffs.
你就能体验到飞一般的感觉
You will experience streamline motion.
完全没有摩擦力
Not friction.
胡说八道
Nonsense.
-拿着，这是“真相”-滚开! 该死的瘾君子！
Take it. This is 'the truth'. -Scram! Bloody addict!
孩子们，今天我们要解决一个关于垂直圆周运动的问题
Children, today we shall solve a problem on vertical circular motion.
让我先给你解释一下这个问题
Let me first explain the problem to you.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
房东阿姨
Aunty.
她走下楼梯时摔倒了
She was walking down the stairs and fell.
她口吐白沫
She is frothing in the mouth.
你好，我需要救护车
Hello. Ambulance.
快来拉尔 · 伯奇酒店，非常紧急
Come to Lal Burj quickly. It's an emergency.
什么? 泡沫? 哪里？
What? Froth? Where?
这就起来了？
You got up?
为了那个二流女人？
For that two-bit woman?
你只是想找个理由站起来
You just want an excuse.
去你的吧！
Damn you!
你会在拜亚哥面前给我们带来耻辱
You will bring disgrace on us in Jeetu Bhaiya's presence.
把赌注里的100卢比给我
Give me my 100 rupees from the bet.
工程师
Engineer.
大自然完成了一半的工作
Nature has done half the job.
水含有盐分
Water contains salt.
只要加盐和柠檬就行了
Just add salt and lemon to it.
柠檬水就做好了
Lemonade is ready.
这个小知识每年拯救一千万儿童的生命
This small tip saves ten million children's lives every year.
太棒了！
It's great!
不是吗？
Isn't it?
现在去拿两个杯子
Go and prepare two glasses now.
三个
Three.
妈妈，乌代的女朋友没有你叫我的次数多
Mummy, Uday's girlfriend does not call him as many times as you call me.
走! 走! 走! 快点！
Go! Go! Go! Come on!
干得好，兄弟! 干得好！
Well done, bro! Well done!
你就快进入印度理工了，加油
You are under the oath of IIT.
如果连一天都坚持不下来，那还怎么看板球比赛？
One can't follow one days, how will one follow test cricket?
T-20版本是专为科塔学生设计的
The T-20 format has been created for Kota students.
IPL（印度超级板球联赛）是未来的趋势
IPL is the future.
要是他们能让尤弗拉伊上场就好了
If only they would take Yuvraj to play.
那就大错特错了
It's very wrong of them.
你说得对，兄弟，这都是政治手腕
You are correct, bro. It's all politics.
兄弟，尤维可以，绝对行
Bro, Yuvi can and Yuvi will.
没错，兄弟，尤弗拉伊会回来的
That's right, bro. Yuvraj will return.
记住我说的话
You can quote me on that.
你觉得呢？
You?
是的
Yes.
他会回来的
He will return.
孩子们，今天我们要解决一个关于冲量动量定理的问题
Children, today we shall solve a problem on impulse momentum theorem
在这节课中，我们将学习计算推动力
In it we shall learn to calculate impulse.
哇! 今天一点声音都没有
Wow! There was no sound today.
你知道你这样真的很变态吧
You know this is really inappropriate.
我为你感到高兴，兄弟
I'm happy for you, buddy.
孩子们，我们今天要解决一个关于摩擦力的问题
Children, we will solve a problem on friction today.
正如你在图片中看到的那样，有两个木块
As you can see in the picture two blocks are made.
这两个木块都放在一个楔子上
Both the blocks are kept on a wedge
两者都是用一根绳子连接起来的
..and both are connected with the help of a string.
blah blah blah…
[Educator speaking]
走吧？
Shall we?
已经六点半了
It is 6:30 already.
我们走
Let's go.
贴近理工学院的一小步
One step closer to IIT
这些是在课堂上完成的
That was done in class.
但我很高兴你今天把作业做完了
But I'm glad today you came with DPP and sheets finished.
这就意味着你完全可以坐得更久
That means this chap is able to sit up longer.
是的
Yes, sir.
饮食问题解决了吗？
Is food and water sorted?
是的，拜亚哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
你能正常拉屎了吗？
Are you able to crap properly?
哦，兄弟！
Oh, Bhaiya!
来吧，你为什么对我这么害羞？
Come along. Why are you being shy with me?
我是你的知心大姐
I am your agony aunt.
我们还有很长的路要走
And we have a long journey together.
每个人都会有这样那样的问题
Everyone has these problems.
我也有
I too have them.
你学过物理化学吗？
Have you been doing Physical Chemistry?
给我根烟
Give me one.
香烟？
A cigarette?
是的
Yes.
你不是戒烟了吗？
Cigarette, Bhaiya?
当我感受不到刺激，情况在我掌控之中的时候
When I don't feel the urge and the situation is under control..
也是可以作弊的
..then you can cheat sometimes.
偶尔作弊是可以的
Cheating occasionally is fine.
但不要经常作弊
As long as it doesn't become a habit.
- 怎么了?-摩托车！
- What's the matter? - Auto!
赶紧去维根纳加尔
Lets rush to Vigyan Nagar.
- 我们走，先生-拜亚哥！
- Let's go, sir. - Bhaiya!
- 拜亚哥!-回头见
- Bhaiya! - I'll see you later.
发生了什么？
What happened?
大自然的召唤？
Nature's call?
是的
Yes.
米娜
Meena.
来吧
Come.
现在才5点
It's only 5 O'clock.
我们走! 快！
Let's go! Come!
书又不会跑
It's always the same..
我们走！
Let's go!
让我把这段看完
I just needed to study one more paragraph.
这段学完会怎样吗？
What will you gain from studying one paragraph?
拜亚哥说了
Jeetu Bhaiya said so.
偶尔作弊是可以的
Occasional cheating is fine.
只要不养成习惯
As long as you don't form a habit.
您拨打的电话无人接听
'The person you are calling is not answering.
请稍后再试”
Please try later.'
他不接我电话
He's not picking my call.
他现在在一个快乐的地方
Now he is in a happy place.